In these clips we are going to talk about the proper way to inspect and adjust your drum style rear brakes.
In this clip we are going to talk about the proper jacking method and supporting method in order to get the rear axle off the ground to inspect and adjust our rear brakes.
Let's get everything out of the way here.
I'll slip my floor jack right underneath.
Okay as you can see here, I have my floor jack cup placed on the lower shock mounting bracket.
What I am going to do once I have my jack located correctly is slip in my pump in handle, lock it into place and begin pumping the jack up.
Once I have it high enough in the air, I am going to install my jack stand.
This is my jack stand here in the picture here so I'll know how high I have to go; just about an inch further.
As you can see my jack stand has a cup shape that is going to fit the roundness of the rear axle perfectly and right there.
Once I have my jack stand there on the rear axle, go ahead and release the hydraulic pressure on my floor jack and that is the proper way to jack up your vehicle and seat your jack stand.